play-cricket.com 2018-02-24

# Play-Cricket

This Website and the Sub Sites attached to it use cookies. For details please click here. By continuing to use this Website or any Sub Sites, you are consenting to the use of these cookies. You can switch off cookies at any time using your browser settings but if you do, this may affect your user experience. 

Please wait...

#####  ENGLAND AND WALES CRICKET BOARD LIMITED 

#####  ECB - General Privacy Policy 

* * *

ABOUT US

This website ( **Website** ) is operated by the England and Wales Cricket Board Limited ( **ECB** ), the UK governing body for cricket as part of its network of sites and sub sites (together, the **ECB Websites** ). 

Additional privacy terms, which form part of this Privacy Policy, apply to personal data and use of, certain ECB Websites and ECB services. Please click on the relevant link(s) below to view the additional terms: 

IT IS IMPORTANT THAT YOU UNDERSTAND AND ARE COMFORTABLE WITH THESE 

TERMS BEFORE USING THE RELEVANT WEBSITE AND/OR SERVICE AND WE 

ENCOURAGE YOU TO TAKE TIME TO READ THEM 

SERVICE  |  LINK   
---|---  
**Play-Cricket additional privacy terms** |  _Click here_  
  
Unless stated otherwise, in the relevant additional privacy terms shown, the ECB is the data controller in respect of all personal data collected on this Website which means that we are responsible for ensuring that we do so in full compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and all other related privacy laws. 

This Privacy Policy explains what information we collect about you, how we use it, and the steps we take to ensure that it is kept secure. We also explain your rights and how to contact us. 

Links to other websites 

Please note, this Website may contains links to other websites that are not controlled by the ECB. These links are provided for your convenience. We are only responsible for the ECB’s privacy practices and the ECB’s security of the ECB Websites. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website that you visit. 

BY USING THIS WEBSITE AND GIVING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US OR TO ANY CRICKET ORGANISATIONS THROUGH OTHER ECB WEBSITES, YOU INDICATE THAT YOU CONSENT TO THE ECB, THE [CRICKET ORGANISATIONS](https://www.ecb.co.uk/county-cricket-boards) AND [ECB PARTNERS](https://www.ecb.co.uk/sponsors-and-partners) COLLECTING AND USING THIS PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. 

CHILDREN

If you are under 16, you will need the permission of your parent or guardian before registering on any ECB Website and we may require your parent or guardian to confirm that they have given permission. We may ask for their contact details so that we can check that they have done so and may carry out checks to confirm that the details you have given us are correct. 

We normally only send newsletters and offers and opportunities to those under 16 where their parent or guardian has given consent to them being sent. Parents or guardians of those under 16 can change their mind at any time (see ‘Newsletters, Offers and Opportunities’ below). 

THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

In order to provide you with the services you require, the ECB will obtain personal information about you (and your parent or guardian if you are under 16) from ECB Websites, telephone conversations, emails and written and verbal communications. These will include, for example, your name, address, email address, phone number and details that are relevant to the service(s) in which you are interested. Occasionally we may ask for date of birth, for example, where the service you require has age related restrictions or ethnicity information to enable us to monitor and ensure compliance with anti-discrimination policies. 

We may supplement the information that you provide with other information that we obtain from our dealings with you or which we receive from other organisations, such as [Cricketing Organisations](https://www.ecb.co.uk/county-cricket-boards) and [ECB Partners](https://www.ecb.co.uk/sponsors-and-partners). 

Information about other people 

If you provide information to us about any person other than yourself, you must ensure that they understand how their information will be used and that you are authorised to disclose it to us, and to consent to its use on their behalf, before doing so. 

IP addresses 

In order to understand how users use our website and services, we may collect IP addresses. 

Cookies 

In common with many other website operators, we may use standard technology called 'cookies' on ECB Websites. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive and they are used to record how you navigate this Website on each visit. 

Our cookies are used to enable us to develop our websites and to enable you to properly navigate ECB Websites. We use cookies to collect personal information to enable us to reflect our customers interests and by noting who has seen which pages, properties and advertisements (including click through from emails), how frequently particular pages are visited and to enable us to determine the most popular areas of ECB Websites. We may use cookies to enrich your experience of using ECB Websites by allowing us to tailor what you see to what we have learned about your preferences during your visits to ECB Websites. Sometimes we may use services of third parties and they may use cookies on our behalf in order to provide their services. 

The particular cookies we use will depend on which ECB Website you are accessing. You can find the cookie information you need by clicking on the link in the table below for the relevant ECB Website 

You may also get cookies (including Flash cookies) from our sponsors and advertisers if you click on their links or adverts. You should check their privacy and security policies to understand how they use these. 

Preventing use of cookies 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent cookies being stored. With experience, you can usually choose to switch off all cookies or to allow only certain ‘trusted’ sites to place cookies. 

For further information on cookies and Flash cookies and how to switch them off see the Infor mation Commissioner’s website at [http://www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) or visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/> or www.aboutcookies.org. 

PLEASE NOTE, IF YOU DO TURN COOKIES OFF, THIS WILL LIMIT THE SERVICE THAT WE ARE ABLE TO PROVIDE TO YOU AND MAY AFFECT YOUR USER EXPERIENCE 

HOW WE WILL USE YOUR INFORMATION

All personal information that we obtain about you and/or any other person whose details you provide will be recorded, used, and protected by us in accordance with current data protection legislation, our  Terms and Conditions  and this Privacy Policy. We will primarily use the personal information: 

  * for registration, membership and general administration (including verification, vetting, security checking, issuing passes and permits as appropriate) 
  * to provide the services you request from us 
  * to communicate with you in the event that any services requested are unavailable or if there is a query or problem with your requests
  * for record keeping purposes
  * to carry out market research so that we can improve the services we offer
  * to track and analyse activity on our website
  * to create an individual profile for you so that we can enhance your user experience, to understand and respect your preferences and to provide newsletters and details of relevant offers and opportunities where you have agreed to receive them 

Disclosing your personal information 

In order to provide our products and services, we may, occasionally, appoint other organisations to carry out some of the processing activities on our behalf. These may include, for example, technology hosts, printing companies and mailing houses. In these circumstances, we will ensure that personal information is properly protected and that it is only used in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

We may also pass relevant personal information to County Cricket Boards, Clubs and Leagues for cricket administration and research purposes where we believe this is appropriate to the service you require or to enable them to understand player activity and develop cricket related services. 

CRICKET ORGANISATIONS

As the national governing body for cricket, the ECB has relationships with other cricket related organisations such as County Cricket Boards, cricket clubs and cricket leagues (each a **Cricket Organisation** ) and some of the goods and services available on or through ECB Websites are provided by those Cricket Organisations. Each Cricket Organisation has its own privacy practices and you should check that you are satisfied with them before you provide any personal information to them. 

ECB PARTNER PROGRAMME 

The ECB teams up with a selection of carefully chosen sponsors and commercial partners. 

For a full list of ECB Partners [click here](https://www.ecb.co.uk/sponsors-and-partners). 

INVITATIONS, NEWSLETTERS, OFFERS AND OPPORTUNITIES 

We and the [Cricket Organisations](https://www.ecb.co.uk/county-cricket-boards) and the [ECB Partners](https://www.ecb.co.uk/sponsors-and-partners) would like to contact you and/or any person whose information you provide to us to invite you to enjoy other services (where you have agreed to us sending an invitation), to provide newsletters and to tell you and/or them about offers and opportunities that are available and about a range of other initiatives in a number of ways, including by post, telephone, text/picture/video message or by email. Details of how to opt-in to or opt-out of receiving details of offers are on relevant pages of this Website, the Sub Sites, in relevant forms you complete and/or in the electronic message you receive. 

Subscribe / Unsubscribe 

You and any other person whose information you have provided to us can change your/their mind about whether you wish to receive details of offers and opportunities at any time by using any of the methods shown below (see the section "How to contact us" below) or by following the instructions with each offer you/they receive. 

SECURITY 

We take the security of personal information seriously. We employ security technology, including firewalls, and Secure Socket Layers to safeguard information and have procedures in place to ensure that our paper and computer systems and databases are protected against unauthorised disclosure, use, loss and damage. 

MONITORING 

We may monitor or record telephone calls for security purposes and to improve the quality of the services we provide to you. 

USE OF YOUR INFORMATION OUTSIDE THE EUROPEAN UNION 

Some of the organisations to which we may disclose personal information may be situated outside of the European Union. In order to provide the products and services you or others whose information you have provided to us, we may need to transfer your/their personal information to these countries some of which do not have laws that protect privacy rights as extensively as in the United Kingdom. If we do transfer your personal information to other territories, we will take proper steps to ensure that the information is protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY 

Privacy laws and practice are constantly developing and we aim to meet high standards. Our policies and procedures are, therefore, under continual review. We may, from time to time, update our security and privacy policies and suggest that you check this page periodically to review our latest policy. 

UPDATING AND CORRECTING INFORMATION 

You may update or correct your personal information online in relevant membership areas or by contacting us in writing or by email (see the section "How to contact us" below). Please include your name, address and/or email address when you contact us as this helps us to ensure that we accept amendments only from the correct person. We encourage you to promptly update your personal information if it changes. If you are providing updates or corrections about another person, we may require you to provide us with proof that you are authorised to provide that information to us. 

YOUR RIGHTS TO ACCESS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

You have the right to receive a copy of the personal information that we hold about you. The same right applies to any other person whose personal information you provide to us. We may charge a small fee towards the cost of administering any request made. The current fee is £10.00. 

HOW TO CONTACT US

Email| [privacy@ecb.co.uk](mailto:privacy@ecb.co.uk)  
---|---  
Mail| Data Protection Officer (Play-Cricket)  
England and Wales Cricket Board Limited  
Lord’s Cricket Ground  
London  
NW8 8QZ  

#####  ENGLAND AND WALES CRICKET BOARD LIMITED 

#####  Play-Cricket.com Privacy Policy 

BELOW ARE ADDITIONAL PRIVACY TERMS THAT APPLY TO YOUR USE OF Play-Cricket. THEY SUPPLEMENT THE GENERAL  PRIVACY POLICY . 

USING THIS WEBSITE AND GIVING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US OR TO ANY CRICKET ORGANISATIONS THROUGH THEIR SUB SITES, YOU INDICATE THAT YOU CONSENT TO THE ECB, THE [CRICKET ORGANISATIONS](https://www.ecb.co.uk/county-cricket-boards) AND [ECB PARTNERS](https://www.ecb.co.uk/sponsors-and-partners) COLLECTING AND USING THIS PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE PRIVACY POLICY (INCLUDING THE TERMS BELOW) 

ABOUT US

play-cricket.com (the **Website** ) is part of the play-cricket network ( **Play-Cricket Site Network** ) of sites which includes a number of sub sites ( **Sub Sites** ) that are administered by England and Wales County Cricket Boards, cricket clubs and cricket leagues ( **Cricket Organisations** ). 

The Website is operated by the England and Wales Cricket Board Limited ( **ECB** ), the UK governing body for cricket. 

In most cases, the ECB is the data controller in respect of all personal data collected on this Website. However, on occasion some Cricket Organisations use this Website to store details of their members in which case, the relevant Cricket Organisation will be the data controller and we will merely host the personal data on their behalf. 

This privacy policy explains what information we collect about you, how we use it, and the steps we take to ensure that it is kept secure. We also explain your rights and how to contact us. 

Cookies 

The following cookies are used on this Website and in Sub Sites: 

Name of cookie | Type of cookie | Purpose of cookie  
---|---|---  
Session cookie_Play-Cricket_session | Strictly necessary (session cookie) |   
remember_checked_on (remember me in login) | Functionality (persistent cookie – deleted after 2 weeks) | Activated by the user at sign in  
hidden announcement_ids | Targeting or advertising (persistent cookie) | Used to record if system administrator alerts have been displayed to the user  
**Certain Cricket Organisations may use additional cookies on their Sub Sites. Those Cricket Organisations will provide details of these additional cookies on their Sub Sites.**  
  
Preventing use of cookies 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent cookies being stored. With experience, you can usually choose to switch off all cookies or to allow only certain ‘trusted’ sites to place cookies. 

For further information on cookies and Flash cookies and how to switch them off see the Information Commissioner’s website at [http://www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) or visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). 

PLEASE NOTE, IF YOU DO TURN COOKIES OFF, THIS WILL LIMIT THE SERVICE THAT WE ARE ABLE TO PROVIDE TO YOU AND MAY AFFECT YOUR USER EXPERIENCE 

HOW WE WILL USE YOUR INFORMATION

All personal information that we obtain about you and/or any other person whose details you provide will be used as described in our Terms and Conditions and our general Privacy Policy. 

There are no additional purposes for this Website.
